[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31c", "question": "Which character did John Ritter play on the TV show \"Three's Company\"?", "answer": "Jack Tripper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b68", "question": "On what cartoon do the main characters live in the fictional town of Bikini Bottom?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae80", "question": "What company printed its first mail-order catalog in 1887?", "answer": "Sears Roebuck and Co.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d1", "question": "Which author built a home called Goldeneye in Jamaica?", "answer": "Ian Fleming", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b8", "question": "In what city would you find Boboli Gardens?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd143ec223966ae8f88be", "question": "What actor wore prosthetic ears while filming \"Jupiter Ascending\"?", "answer": "Channing Tatum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9323574a5ce6b56b8236", "question": "Who was the Roman goddess of youth?", "answer": "Juventas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0a", "question": "What year did Anna Nicole Smith die from a drug overdose?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb671b5dad637d903c883b", "question": "If you order \"murgh\" from the menu at an Indian restaurant, what meat will you get?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7aa", "question": "What is the atomic number for thallium?", "answer": "81", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c36", "question": "The Newbery Medal is awarded annually for what genre of writing?", "answer": "Children's literature", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c382", "question": "What poisonous spider can be identified by a small red hourglass-shaped marking on the underside of its body?", "answer": "Black widow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c607", "question": "The Asteroid Belt can be found between which two planets?", "answer": "Mars and Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdc", "question": "Who was the only president of the Confederate States of America?", "answer": "Jefferson Davis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab88", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffc3e1cf6db9ac4808cfc", "question": "What part of Russia is surrounded by Lithuania and Poland?", "answer": "Kaliningrad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339388", "question": "What is the Voight-Kampff machine in the movie \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "A lie detector", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb088ebcf631c2414a13b5d", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what is the language of the White Walkers?", "answer": "Skroth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9a", "question": "What year was Jack the Ripper active?", "answer": "1888", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c1", "question": "What US state is represented by the figures of Will Rogers and Sequoyah in the Capitol's Statuary Hall?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c330", "question": "What is known as the \"Droste Effect\"?", "answer": "The effect of an image appearing within itself", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937eb9a08d98002fdd633b0", "question": "Chopin played what instrument as a child?", "answer": "The piano", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27b", "question": "What does a panophobe fear?", "answer": "Everything", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa5658c73aa70ea0b70b2a", "question": "What color do people wear for the New Year in Brazil?", "answer": "White", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c973", "question": "What's the largest artery in the human body?", "answer": "The aorta\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d06d67870e6f05ba600858", "question": "What metals is Bell metal an alloy of?", "answer": "Tin and copper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbd52ea00d154d7af00b8db", "question": "Which band recorded the song \"Killing in the Name\"?", "answer": "Rage Against the Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe90a9401dd7bf43be5e89d", "question": "In 1901, Guglielmo Marconi received the first transatlantic wireless signal from atop Signal Hill in which city?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b54c", "question": "What two colours make purple?", "answer": "Red and Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d73", "question": "What ship was commanded by Jack Sparrow?", "answer": "Black Pearl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea345bff048f679a45aaf7", "question": "What is the name of the biggest part of the human brain?", "answer": "The cerebrum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c079", "question": "What is the fear of knees known as?", "answer": "Genuphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce9", "question": "Tuesday Weld played Thalia Menninger on what TV show?", "answer": "The Many Loves of Dobie Gillis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c59", "question": "Who played the role of the bodyguard in the 1992 movie \"The Bodyguard\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c67c877e98cb977789ba", "question": "Where are the Mayan ruins of Tikal located?", "answer": "Guatemala", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ee", "question": "On what continent is Mt. Vesuvius?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ad", "question": "Stockholm is located along what sea?", "answer": "The Baltic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d06c78870e6f05ba600853", "question": "As the speed of a body approaches the speed of light, its mass approaches what?", "answer": "Infinity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d06ee1a1c922dd1ac64b2", "question": "Where would you find the Pont Neuf bridge?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4b5749076251badbeac3", "question": "For what does NAACP stand?", "answer": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecccbdec223966ae8f88a4", "question": "In what movie did Benedict Cumberbatch wear dentures that were an exact replica of Alan Turing's 60-year old set of false teeth?", "answer": "\"The Imitation Game\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd4177e83c707845b2159", "question": "Which famous actor was offered the role of Neo in the film \"The Matrix\" but turned it down?", "answer": "Will Smith turned down the role of Neo to instead star in \"Wild Wild West\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5ef46ce05a3942286e3c", "question": "Who had a hit song with the theme from the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ray Parker, Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b48b", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a4", "question": "What was the name of the high school in the TV show \"Our Miss Brooks\"?", "answer": "Madison High", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d2", "question": "What does an Enigma machine do?", "answer": "Ciphers and deciphers messages", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a5a820565ad31a57c7cf", "question": "Which Mediterranean island once campaigned to become a U.S. state?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af30", "question": "From what terrible disease did Robert the Bruce suffer?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c5", "question": "What is the only phase of the Moon that can produce a solar eclipse?", "answer": "New Moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba659874c93a3298b2158", "question": "What is the nickname given to Negan's bat in the TV show \"The Walking Dead\"?", "answer": "Lucille", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9b", "question": "What movie did the villain Harry Powell appear in?", "answer": "The Night of the Hunter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a171", "question": "What is the name of Marty's band in the film \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "The Pinheads", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77bc0ab2c8f322317fee", "question": "Which holiday did Canada Day replace in 1982?", "answer": "Dominion Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab48", "question": "Which African coast is Somalia located on?", "answer": "East", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c2", "question": "How many US soldiers were killed in the movie \"Black Hawk Down\"?", "answer": "18", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7c", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Doris Mann in the novel \"Postcards from the Edge\"?", "answer": "Debbie Reynolds", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e5f0e89d274615ecf514535", "question": "The \"Sherwood Forest Plantation\", home to U.S. President John Tyler, is located in which U.S. state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72d", "question": "What is Santa's name in France?", "answer": "Pere Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbe", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"Kika and The Cook\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e0", "question": "What magazine introduced a paper doll named Betsy in 1951?", "answer": "McCall's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c455", "question": "What creature takes its name from Aboriginal words for \"no drink\"?", "answer": "Koala", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66ae952a821ff76ae8b0b", "question": "Confucianism effectively became the common philosophy of the Chinese empire during which dynasty?", "answer": "Han Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99bea21a8909e5c332d31", "question": "Who wrote the 1981 novel \"Who Censored Roger Rabbit?\"?", "answer": "Gary K. Wolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a994", "question": "Which cuisine gave us kimchi and bulgogi?", "answer": "Korean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d5", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Old Fuss and Feathers\"?", "answer": "Winfield Scott", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a82e", "question": "Pashto is the official language of which country?", "answer": "Afghanistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c48", "question": "Who is the main character in Ayn Rynd's \"The Fountainhead\"?", "answer": "Howard Roark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a3236c0f9723ab15cb4a", "question": "What did Pocahontas change her name to after she converted to Christianity?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dfd", "question": "What \"Suddenly Susan\" actor ended up committing suicide?", "answer": "David Strickland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16973f7c52aae91cc07d1", "question": "In 1861, Julius Sturgis started the first US commercial bakery that made what?", "answer": "Pretzels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa39b4c73aa70ea0b70ada", "question": "Which country does Denmark share its only land border with?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae863c07f28483af1e7fdcb", "question": "How many states does India have?", "answer": "29", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb57de5dad637d903c880c", "question": "What is the name of the oldest bridge in Venice, which crosses the city's famous Grand Canal?", "answer": "The Ponte di Rialto, or Rialto Bridge, was built between 1588 and 1591 to span the width of the Grand Canal.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb14a65ff7d326b622a69", "question": "During which month is the longest day in the Southern hemisphere?", "answer": "December", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6016009afe83fe1f2a824c56", "question": "What was the subject of the first color photograph?", "answer": "A tartan ribbon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d0a", "question": "What British actor published his memoirs in 2008 entitled \"My Word is My Bond\"?", "answer": "Roger Moore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93a", "question": "What hometown of Scott Joplin and Ross Perot is named for the three states whose border it sits near?", "answer": "Texarkana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338993", "question": "Who composed the \"Brandenburg Concertos\"?", "answer": "Johann Sebastian Bach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff6687952a821ff76ae8b05", "question": "In the Bible, who are Abraham's brothers?", "answer": "Nahor and Haran", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff1402cb0ee8c595b6d3996", "question": "Michelangelo's David sculpture was originally modeled after which hero of myth?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5eb739095e259d7869087330", "question": "Which organ has 4 chambers?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede3d16ce05a3942286dd7", "question": "Who was the voice of Mr. Potato Head in \"Toy Story\"?", "answer": "Don Rickles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd1", "question": "Chablis comes from which French wine region?\u00a0", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6f", "question": "What was Rod Stewart's first #1 song?", "answer": "Maggie May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47c", "question": "What is a small group of islands called?", "answer": "Archipelago", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b5", "question": "Which French fashion designer created the conical bra for Madonna's \"Blond Ambition\" tour?", "answer": "Jean-Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901da79709c1c34536e6eaf", "question": "In ice hockey, how many players for each team are allowed on the ice at the same time?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a959d61d1b4d384d5d67b", "question": "\"White Room\" was a hit off which Cream album?", "answer": "Wheels of Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e805b24f84e0b9f9ffc2", "question": "Perth is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Western Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59636d9b967692ea851899ae", "question": "The surface of what is typically 70% water and 10% ice?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339783", "question": "What album earned the Bee Gees a Grammy Award in 1978?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2b", "question": "Who wrote \"De Profundis\" while in prison?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908d", "question": "Which Roman God was the equivalent of the Greek God Dionysus?", "answer": "Bacchus, Liber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfd", "question": "The eyewear brand Ray Ban was founded what year?", "answer": "1937", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5aab205e8ec9cac6c946a862", "question": "As what is Formosa now known?", "answer": "Taiwan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339305", "question": "In the movie \"Gremlins\", what is the name of the little Mogwai given to Billy?", "answer": "Gizmo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3cd", "question": "What was the nationallity of Rasputin?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9de5ee748bb36357acde5", "question": "Who played Matlock in the muder mystery series of the same name?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3e3244f0f6af5b066647", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 21?", "answer": "Zepto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6aa", "question": "Which side of a ship is \"starboard\"?", "answer": "Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76941eec85e375820b2af", "question": "In which sea would you find the Cayman Islands?", "answer": "Caribbean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399cf", "question": "What famous blind musician has the real given last name Judkins?", "answer": "Stevie Wonder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8af5ec223966ae8f8835", "question": "In what book of the Bible did the prison warden find Andy's rock hammer in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Exodus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d43", "question": "Which Claude Monet painting is attributed to giving the Impressionist Movement its name?", "answer": "Impression, Sunrise", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3fd", "question": "Who succeeded James Garfield as US President?", "answer": "Chester A. Arthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523c05736d4be723796b34", "question": "On what day does Canada celebrate its birthday?", "answer": "July 1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f07", "question": "What author created the character of Father Brown?", "answer": "G. K. Chesterton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ac8101dd7bf43be5e76c", "question": "Which common houseplant is said to make burns heal faster?", "answer": "Aloe Vera", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3924c73aa70ea0b70ad8", "question": "Explorers named Rhode Island after resemblance to which part of the world?", "answer": "The Greek island, Rhodes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41a", "question": "What ancient creature took its name from the Greek words for \"terrible lizard\"?", "answer": "Dinosaur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d87", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Charly\" based on?", "answer": "Flowers for Algernon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be580ca5415ba52ed6f0ab9", "question": "Doha is the capital of which West Asian country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3e", "question": "What does blitzkrieg mean?", "answer": "Lightning war", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75f", "question": "In what year did the Soviet Union launch its first Sputnik satellite?", "answer": "1957", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d0", "question": "Sound Navigation Ranging is better known as what?", "answer": "Sonar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c1", "question": "What word was intentionally omitted from the screenplay of The Godfather?", "answer": "Mafia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c365", "question": "What fruit did Algerian priest Pierre Clement create in 1902?", "answer": "Clementine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa564ec73aa70ea0b70b29", "question": "What type of dancing is usually performed in conjunction with May Day celebrations in England?", "answer": "Morris dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c301", "question": "Is it true that the female penguin does not incubate her eggs?", "answer": "Yes, the male penguin does.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b699285e762b54eb9be9423", "question": "What is the technical term for a 20-sided die?", "answer": "Icosahedron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb93", "question": "Which commemorative US state quarter depicts salmon leaping in front of a mountain on its reverse side?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c894fbde8045e48466dd", "question": "What are the gases that surround the Earth called?", "answer": "Atmosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65ec91f3c0ead6880d62f", "question": "Which Christmas tradition used to be a year-round practice?", "answer": "Caroling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4a", "question": "In 1803 The Louvre was renamed to what?", "answer": "Mus\u00e9e Napol\u00e9on", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c9", "question": "What state is nicknamed the \"Beehive State\"?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a522", "question": "How many neighbors does Lesotho have?", "answer": "Only 1", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75e", "question": "Pepsi Twist was a Pepsi flavored with what?", "answer": "Lemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb0", "question": "Which was the first country to leave the Commonwealth in 1949?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1ceb97bd84c0ea43ad43b", "question": "Who is Thomas John Woodward better known as?", "answer": "Tom Jones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d23", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"National Velvet\"?", "answer": "Horse racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8c56ec223966ae8f8848", "question": "The 1994 \"Leon\" was the motion-picture debut of which one of its stars?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e93a8c6d6f11f394a3b2d58", "question": "In the manga series \"Bleach\", what is the name of Izura Kira's zanpakuto?", "answer": "Wabisuke", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339714", "question": "Who played the role of Ross on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "David Schwimmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f7eeb4e2c7fbd389674d", "question": "What year was Strongbow cider introduced to the market?", "answer": "1962", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc3", "question": "Where in the Americas did Europeans first settle?", "answer": "L'Anse aux Meadows, Newfoundland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a860", "question": "Belgium's name is derived from what Roman province?", "answer": "Gallia Belgica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339590", "question": "What movie starring Bruce Willis contains the line \"I see dead people\"?", "answer": "The Sixth Sense", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96f", "question": "What did the \"Manhattan\" project set out to develop?", "answer": "Atomic bomb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339117", "question": "What year did H. G. Wells publish \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "1896", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f9", "question": "What is the correct name for a baby seal, baby shark, or baby bat?", "answer": "Pup", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b140", "question": "The first time Ronald Reagan voted for a U.S. president, who did he cast his ballot for?", "answer": "FDR", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc6beec223966ae8f8887", "question": "What is Neo's official name in the film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Anthony A. Anderson, which is why Agent Smith refers to him as \"Mr. Anderson\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c39", "question": "What is the name of the cafe in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0b", "question": "What US state is the Catalina Island located in?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69b2420565ad31a57c75c", "question": "Which World War II battle saw the greatest number of tanks used in world history?", "answer": "The Battle of Kursk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a0", "question": "How many minutes does it take to complete a 12 round boxing match?", "answer": "47 minutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904998ccf93664eb1048692", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd5", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"canyon\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a1", "question": "Who is known as Slim Shady?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015eaccfe83fe1f2a824bf5", "question": "What does the color blue represent in the American flag?", "answer": "Blue symbolizes vigilance, perseverance and justice.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33e", "question": "How long does it take the moon to revolve around the Earth, to the nearest day?", "answer": "27", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aa8820565ad31a57c81a", "question": "In which German city did Joseph Stalin, Winston Churchill and President Franklin D Roosevelt meet in 1945?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3c", "question": "What plan was developed by General Winfield Scott to defeat the Confederate Army?", "answer": "Anaconda Plan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c7c8877e98cb977789d7", "question": "Which Mediterranean city has an area nicknamed \"The White City\"?", "answer": "Tel Aviv", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a47112f2a7826b9b8730", "question": "A medicine that hastens the emptying of the bowels is called a what?", "answer": "Laxative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b57186167df192a942e335e", "question": "Which continent would you find the \"Strait of Magellan\" in?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa79", "question": "Which is Earth's smallest ocean?", "answer": "Arctic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc81aec223966ae8f888e", "question": "What is the name of the spider that paralyzes Frodo in the film \"The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King\"?", "answer": "Shelob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb109f83302ff91e464a3", "question": "What company makes the Larry O'Brien Trophy?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e5", "question": "What US state is home to the Sundance Film Festival?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db751e0ab2c8f322317fe4", "question": "Peridot is the birthstone for which month?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36d", "question": "What soup is likely to be on the menu in Poland or Russia?", "answer": "Borscht", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b35", "question": "What is the name of the winged horse of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Pegasus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6008dcfef4f3bc4a292f861d", "question": "Whose \"Civil Disobedience\" essay inspired Dr. Martin Luther King King. Jr.?", "answer": "Henry David Thoreau (Thoreau wrote it after he was imprisoned for protesting slavery by refusing to pay his poll tax.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe25717658e585fda9cfa3a", "question": "What destructive party item was banned in Hollywood on Halloween starting in 2004?", "answer": "Silly String", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff667c952a821ff76ae8aff", "question": "Which governing body classified tomatoes as a vegetable in the United States?", "answer": "U.S. Supreme Court (In a case regarding a tariff on imported vegetables, entrepreneur John Nix argued tomatoes are a fruit.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12d48e39efa6330e0feca", "question": "What is the world's longest highway?", "answer": "Pan-American Highway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e14", "question": "George Orwell's \"Animal Farm\" is a roman \u00e0 clef for what historical event?", "answer": "The Russian Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c662", "question": "What is the longest and heaviest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Femur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f63301dd7bf43be5e830", "question": "What is the traditional gift for a 40th wedding anniversary?", "answer": "Ruby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde5107c6c6b019850c9a8c", "question": "Mariner IV sent the first pictures of which planet back to Earth?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the three-eyed fish named?", "answer": "Blinky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffac71cf6db9ac4808cf1", "question": "What country was the modern bicycle invented in?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae92a7574a5ce6b56b8230", "question": "Who wrote the play \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ed", "question": "What Harry Potter character has the patronus of a hare/bunny?", "answer": "Luna Lovegood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedd9146ce05a3942286d78", "question": "What was the name of the last game released as a physical cartridge for the Super Nintendo?", "answer": "\"Fire Emblem: Thracia 776\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8d", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Goodbye, Mr. Chips\"?", "answer": "Greer Garson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e139e748bb36357acdf4", "question": "What is the reality TV show based on the Robertson Family?", "answer": "Duck Dynasty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5de65a0bf89b9ec3da2d335d", "question": "What device controlled the air/fuel mixture in automobile engines before the advent of Fuel Injection", "answer": "The Carburetor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Hello, beautiful. No ring, I see. So you are only arranged to be married.\"?", "answer": "Apu Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69e5120565ad31a57c781", "question": "\"Night of Broken Glass\" was also called what?", "answer": "Kristallnacht", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b93", "question": "Frank Sinatra died on the exact same night as the series finale of what popular TV show?", "answer": "Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f78", "question": "What was Buddy Holly's backing band?", "answer": "The Crickets", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4f", "question": "Who published his Civil War poetry in \"Drum-Taps\"?", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a385", "question": "What is the capital of Estonia?", "answer": "Tallinn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bccb", "question": "What werewolf-themed cereal briefly joined Count Chocula on store shelves in 1974?", "answer": "Fruit Brute", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5d666ce05a3942286e2a", "question": "Which NFL teams always play on Thanksgiving Day?", "answer": "Detroit Lions and Dallas Cowboys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4ba949076251badbeac6", "question": "The first North American\u00a0English seasonal camp was founded where?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland -- In 1583, Sir\u00a0Humphrey Gilbert, by the\u00a0royal prerogative\u00a0of\u00a0Queen Elizabeth I, founded\u00a0St. John's.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba3", "question": "Who wrote the play, \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4e", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Girl in the Kremlin\"?", "answer": "Natalie Darryl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc04", "question": "The correction fluid Liquid Paper was invented in what year?", "answer": "1951", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64f", "question": "From which US university did Richard Nixon obtain a law degree?", "answer": "Duke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac90", "question": "Which US robbers had the surnames Parker and Barrow?", "answer": "Bonnie and Clyde", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30f", "question": "Theobromine, a substance found in what aphrodisiac, is poisonous to dogs?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcc", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by The Beau Brummels?", "answer": "Laugh Laugh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e8038bde59ea584496fe9d", "question": "What year did Dodie Smith publish the book \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "1956", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bb4cd96d05b23b28164c", "question": "Which President was the first to officially recognize Hanukkah?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ef0e08d98002fdd633dd", "question": "What is the fear of numbers known as?", "answer": "Numerophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be1f", "question": "Which company makes the \"Golden Crisp\" cereal?", "answer": "Post", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3235f5bf195a31e15d73b4", "question": "Who played the electric piano on the Beatles track \"Get Back\"?", "answer": "Billy Preston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a6", "question": "What is the literal translation of the word Brandy?", "answer": "Burned wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50d", "question": "How many lanes does an Olympic swimming pool have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5902a1becad1ec93f27df779", "question": "In the beer world, what does the abbreviation IBU stand for?", "answer": "International Bitterness Units", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b161", "question": "What year was the United Nations found?", "answer": "1945", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a823", "question": "What Caribbean island nation's name comes from the Portuguese word meaning \"bearded ones\"?", "answer": "Barbados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c531", "question": "What is the first element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a8376c0f9723ab15cb64", "question": "What is the first animal of the Chinese zodiac?", "answer": "Rat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c8defbde8045e48466e2", "question": "What do plants produce through photosynthesis?", "answer": "Plants use energy from the sun to turn carbon dioxide into food. Carbohydrates and oxygen are the end result of photosynthesis.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b18", "question": "What is Mozart's full name?", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b0", "question": "What do the Scoville Heat Units indicate?", "answer": "The amount of capsaicin present", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca51", "question": "What fruit is \"Citrus grandis\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a125", "question": "What do \"Tom\", \"Dick\", and \"Harry\" refer to in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "The escape tunnels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88b", "question": "What capital city is built around the famous Plaza Mayor and Puerta del Sol?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f9f3f3eaf848b908361b86b", "question": "What amusement ride was first ridden in 1893 at the World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago?", "answer": "The Ferris Wheel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c98d", "question": "Who was the first female American in space?", "answer": "Sally Ride", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72d", "question": "Dover is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30f", "question": "What war saw the first soldier buried at Arlington's Tomb of the Unknowns?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c8f2fbde8045e48466e4", "question": "Which farm animal is known as a ram, ewe, and lamb?", "answer": "Sheep -- Female sheep are called ewes, male sheep are called rams, and baby sheep are called lambs.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3d", "question": "What is a Texas Ruby Red?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a9", "question": "Trepanation is the practice of drilling holes where?", "answer": "In the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b452", "question": "Which famed hunter, scout, and showman of the Old West nicknamed his rifle \"Lucretia Borgia\"?", "answer": "Buffalo Bill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34a", "question": "Which country was the setting for the TV serial \"The Flame Trees of Thika\"?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef5", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Chingachgook?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d33", "question": "What 1813 novel was turned into a movie starring Keira Knightly in 2005?", "answer": "Pride and Prejudice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b703", "question": "What is an albatross in golf scoring?", "answer": "3 under par", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899b2560d398dc9cf7a69a", "question": "What type of animal is a Samoyed?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b54e01dd7bf43be5e7ce", "question": "What are Bic pens named after?", "answer": "A version of the founder's name", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc26", "question": "What festival is held on the last Wednesday of August each year in Bunol, Spain?", "answer": "La Tomatina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96f2d23c87fd04dd15e40", "question": "What year did the Times Square Ball Drop first take place?", "answer": "1907, welcoming 1908", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96c2723c87fd04dd15e20", "question": "Frank Sinatra rewrote \"High Hopes\" for what US president's campaign?", "answer": "John F Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b370a81c3f17ccc40c8e17", "question": "Pubs are said to have evolved from what Anglo-Saxon establishment that started to appear in the 5th century?", "answer": "Alehouses", "category": "History"}, {"id": "5a25f14f6682715b82711cde", "question": "What year was the ice cream cone patented in the US?", "answer": "1903", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c751877e98cb977789cb", "question": "What body of water separates Australia and New Zealand?", "answer": "Tasman Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc1f1ec223966ae8f8870", "question": "Who\u2019s the only athlete who ever lit the cauldron for an Olympics and then won a gold medal at those same games?", "answer": "Cathy Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c514", "question": "A hair that curls back on itself and penetrates the skin is known as what?", "answer": "Ingrown", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90d62c52800b05cac20f1f", "question": "What two planets in our Solar System possess no moons?", "answer": "Mercury and Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff9", "question": "Who won a Nobel Peace Prize in 1906 for his work at ending the Russo-Japanese War?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121c2b63c99d48cd169b12", "question": "Norman Rockwell painted 323 covers for which magazine?", "answer": "\"Saturday Evening Post\" -- The magazine featured Rockwell\u2019s work from 1916 to 1963.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae7", "question": "In what year did both \"Mad Magazine\" and \"The National Enquirer\" debut?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10d", "question": "In ancient Greece, what color hair was associated with prostitution?", "answer": "Blonde", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c326", "question": "The zero of which two temperature scales is known as \"Absolute Zero\"?", "answer": "Kelvin and Rankine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdd3eec223966ae8f8902", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51402ff04d658268c92e0", "question": "What Chinese princess commanded the \"Army of the Lady\"?", "answer": "Princess Pingyang,\u00a0the daughter of Emperor Gaozu of Tang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d0", "question": "Whitney Houston and Mariah Carey collaborated on the hit single \"When You Believe\" for what 1998 film?", "answer": "The Prince of Egypt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b0", "question": "What phenomenon is named for the French words for \"already seen\"?", "answer": "Deja vu", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a192", "question": "In what 1985 movie did Ally Sheedy play the role of Allison Reynolds?", "answer": "The Breakfast Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba4fb874c93a3298b214b", "question": "What does Mount Snowdon roughly translate to from Old English?", "answer": "Snow hill", "category": "geography"}]